Hey...
Rin.
Wake up.
Come over here.
It was just a dream.
There's nothing to worry about.
Huh?
ashita no koto wa wakannai
We don't know what'll happen tomorrow.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
This feels different from a sacrifice.
nanika ga chigau
Something feels different.
batsu ge-mu ja nante omowanai
I'm not thinking of it as a punishment game.
de nande na no ka wa wakannai
I still don't know why.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
Even though I don't quite feel satisfied with that,
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
there's no question that you're important to me now.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
There's nothing in this world that's endless.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
Isn't it painful having to cry?
ai no Sweet Drops, Sweet Drops
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itai ne
Don't you want to keep dreaming forever?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
Don't you want to be kinder?
kimi to iraretara Happy
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy.
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
Don't you think girls can be strong?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
Even though we can be weak sometimes.
bokura no negai wa Happy Happy Happy
Our wish is for happy, happy, happy.
sonna hibi mo Happy
Those days can also be happy.
Just wanna make you happy
Just wanna make you happy.
Here, I'll take one, too.
Grandpa used to make them, too!
Is that right?
You know what? I want my own knife.
You're still a little too young...
They have ones for kids, too!
Seriously?
I'll think about it.
Come on, let's eat.
We've gotta get going soon.
Okay.
Isn't the baby cute?
Yeah.
I am Kawachi, a relative of Kaga Rin-san's father.
Right now, Rin-san and I... Rin and I are living together.
Oh...
Um... You are Yoshii Masako-san...
You are Rin's mother, correct?
Um...
M-Me?
Yes...
I'd like to meet you in person and talk about something.
Anywhere near you would be fine, so if you could pick a place...
Place? Um...
Oh, I don't know... I guess in the shopping area, at the...
Sorry, I don't have any idea where you live...
This is so cute!
More crafts, Mom?
You made this flower, too?
That's right. It's called embroidery.
Wow! That's amazing!
When you get a little bigger, I'll teach you how to do it.
Really?
Since you're so good with your hands, Rin-chan.
So what's your plan?
I can't say until I meet her...
Well, keep an eye on Rin while I'm out.
Daikichi...
It's important.
So have a good long talk with her.
Mom's been looking forward to spending time with Rin-chan anyway.
This is really close to Grandpa's house...
Welcome!
Are you alone, sir?
One more person will be coming.
Non-smoking, please...
Watch out! You're gonna spill!
The stress just keeps building...
Believe me, I've been there!
Americano, please.
Right, one Americano!
Would you like anything else?
No, thank you.
This is very nice, Saionji-sensei!
But I'd expect no less from you.
Now you just need to give each character some trauma,
two or three problems each...
D-Don't you think that's overdoing it?
No, I think that'd be perfect!
It doesn't make sense...
After she took the time to erase every trace of herself from Grandpa's house...
Does she still live near here?
Then I'll see you soon, Sensei.
Thank you for coming.
Pretty careless for someone who ran off...
Mama, I have to pee!
Yeah, yeah. Just hold it a few minutes.
Hello? Where are you now?
I'm already in the restaurant.
S-Souichi-san...
Wrong. I'm his grandson.
She's like a little kid...
U-Um... I'm sorry about that.
It's just that you look so much like him...
That's okay...
In fact, just recently, someone else told me that...
But still...
Souichi-san had a kinder look about him...
Yeah...
I brought a photo of Rin.
Thank you...
It was taken at the beginning of the year.
At a rice cake pounding party at her nursery school.
She seems...
so much like a young lady...
Before, someone called you "Sensei"...
W-Were you watching?
But the name is...
That's my pen name.
Sorry...
I'm totally out of it after pulling an all-nighter because of deadline hell...
Hah...?
Is that work the reason you left Rin behind?
Um...
And apparently you made Rin think that you were just the housekeeper,
but is that from when she was born?
Mm... My work is the reason.
But it's also true that I was Souichi-san's maid.
I had resolved not to think of Rin as my daughter as early as during pregnancy.
S-Sorry. I'm not sure I understand...
For the longest time, I wasn't popular at all...
Then, just as I was about to finally land a major assignment,
I found out I was pregnant...
And it's not the kind of work you can do and raise a kid at the same time...
But Souichi-san encouraged me to have the child nevertheless...
Every day, I'd either work or stay in bed, and just got fatter and flabbier...
But even so, weirdly enough...
When Rin was born, I thought she was so cute, and my heart went out to her.
Weirdly enough...?
That's why, even while telling myself that Rin wasn't my daughter,
I tried desperately to both work and raise her.
But it was tough trying to be a day person...
And sometimes I have to go out at night for meetings,
which means being up late...
It was just physically impossible...
Um... I hear that Rin stayed with you in an apartment at night?
Yes...
Did you ever go out at night then?
Well, it was more the middle of the night.
Rin was already sleeping, so I went out for a little while...
And sometimes Souichi-san watched her then...
Even now, Rin occasionally wakes up after midnight.
Didn't you ever think about how she'd feel when she did,
and no one was next to her?
But... how else was I supposed to raise a child on my own?
Well, my grandfather wanted the three of you to be a family, didn't he?
Do you have a problem with me continuing to live with Rin?
No.
I'm no longer Rin's mother,
so I don't have the right to make those kinds of choices.
Even though it's beyond dispute that Rin was in your belly?
Th-That has nothing to do with it!
How do you actually feel about Rin?
Is she important to you or not?
I-I don't know...
Um... I just have one favor to ask...
What is it?
When that girl goes to school, please let her use your family name.
Hah? My family name?
If her surname is different from that of her guardian,
I'm sure she'll have a rough time...
Would you just promise me that?
I know where you're coming from, but...
Still, I can't promise that.
She's always been Kaga Rin up to now.
I don't think a person's name is such a simple thing to change.
I'm a woman,
so I don't have any great affection for or attachment to my family name.
Anyway, it might change one day.
Rin's a woman, too, so she probably feels the same way.
Yeah, but Rin's still six.
And that's not what I'm talking about.
Besides, it's just your own personal opinion!
Only one thing is important!
Her name, "Rin," which Souichi-san gave her.
Now, excuse me!
Look...
I'm a man, so I don't really get what you're saying.
However, I can talk to her about it.
Talk to her about it?
You'd make that little girl decide?!
Don't you think that's cruel?!
I...
I'm thinking about what's best for Rin.
And making the decision for her is what would be cruel.
First, I've got to ask Rin how she feels.
After that, the two of us will decide together,
and afterward, I'll let you know what the answer is.
It sounds like she's no good!
I'm sure of it!
Who would abandon a cute little girl like that?!
It's irrational!
Well, she does at least worry about Rin...
It's just, she's a little odd.
It's like she's not aware of the other people involved in her mess.
What are you talking about?!
Naturally, a mother would worry about her daughter!
But if she was really worried, she'd want to see her!
Now, now. We don't know the woman's circumstances. Have an orange.
What did Grandpa ever see in her?
Well, at this stage, that hardly matters...
The thing is, she demanded that when Rin starts school, she use my surname.
Oh, well, I agree with that.
Of course a child should have the same family name as her guardian.
Well, yeah... I understand, but...
How am I supposed to explain that to Rin?
When she's already got a name of her own...
Well, she's a girl,
so her family name will change anyway when she gets married...
That again?!
What again?
It's much more preferable for her to use our family name at school
than let someone joke about her differing name and hurt her feelings.
And you think she can keep all that straight?
There's a lot going on, even in elementary school.
I just don't want things to be difficult for her.
Fine, I'll adopt Rin.
Wha...?!
As long as she doesn't object.
That way, she'll really be Kawachi Rin.
Yeah, that way's more natural.
Don't talk so glibly about something that important!
I'm not being glib!
This is something that must be decided, am I right?!
It's all the same whether it's now or later!
Easy, easy...
It's not all the same!
Yes, it is! It absolutely is!
I'm not passing the baton to anyone else.
That would be the worst thing I could do to Rin.
If it's for Rin, I can accept my fate.
Here.
This is mine?
Yep, it's yours.
But you can only use it when I'm next to you, got it?
If you promise me that, you get to use the knife.
I promise!
You know what, I'll make curry for you!
You serious?
Tonight!
Let's make it tomorrow...
Huh?
I forget, do I push or pull?
Give it here a sec...
Oh, like this...
Daikichi, you're good at that!
Yeah, well, I lived alone for a long time...
Now you try.
Go nice and slow...
Don't drink the bathwater.
I won't.
Go up to your shoulders and count to ten.
Okay.
One...
One, two...
two, three...
three, four, shut the door...
five, six, pick up sticks, seven...
four, five, six...
Daikichi, you're counting slow!
Don't be in such a hurry to eat.
Okay.
Hey, Rin...
What?
Never mind...
Your curry's delicious!
Do I have to do it as long as you?
Oh, no... That's okay...
Mm... You know...
I'm not your father...
I know.
But I'm not your big brother either, right?
Nobody thinks that!
That was just an example!
The question is, what am I then?
Daikichi!
That's my name...
Listen, and this is only if you aren't against it...
What I'm trying to say... How should I put it...?
Uh... What do you...
Rin, what would you think...
about me becoming your real father?
Daikichi, you...
become my father?
So, if we did that, your name would become Kawachi Rin...
Kawachi... Rin.
No.
"No"?
Don't you think it'd be better if you had a father?
My father is Grandpa.
My name is Kaga Rin and I like it.
It's the same name as Grandpa's.
That's important.
I see...
Daikichi should just stay Daikichi.
Daikichi?
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
This is sweat!
It's still only March...
Oh, shut up!
Just open your mouth!
It was open, but you were crying!
I said I wasn't crying!
Move your head up a little more.
Okay.
You know, this'll always be your home...
Yeah.
Congratulations on Graduating from Nursery School
We mustn't forget what we believe.
Because the morning will surely come.
We mustn't lose our dreams.
Because one day they will surely come true.
The first step... Step to tomorrow...
Starting today, everything will be new!
Build that courage up, nice and big...
And take that first step out!
I understand.
You're going to get fat, you know.
That's fine. Either way, I'm good for nothing.
Give me one.
Forget it.
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
It's a sunny Sunday, early in the afternoon.
kyou wa doko e yukou?
Where should we go today?
kayoi nareta itsumo no michi ga
This path I've grown so used to taking
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
seems to be shining brightly,
terasu atatakai taiyou to
as long as the warm sun is shining
tonari ni kimi ga ireba
and you are here beside me.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
I feel like frolicking about.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe wa dokomademo
Our voices can go anywhere.
mou High High High
I'm already high, high, high.
maiagaru kaze ni nori
I'm riding on the rising wind.
utae Life Life Life
Let's sing, life, life, life.
koe mo tobihaneru
Even our voices will be bouncing.
Only babies get held like that!
That's what Sayaka-chan said!
Hah?! That's not true!
There are times when even adults want to be held in someone's arms.
Adults?! Why?!
I don't know myself.
Is it still okay to be held, even after I become a first-grader?
Why, sure!
I'll hold you no matter how old you are...
W-What?!
I'm sorry.
I should've held you before.
Hah?
I'll hold you the next time you cry, Daikichi.
What the...?
Don't worry!
Am I raising Rin or is she raising me?
Sometimes I wonder...
Fly through the sky, pass through the water and run over the land!
I'm called Kaga Rin.
Good afternoon.
Today, I start 1st grade.
When I grow up, I want to be a ninja!
Daikichi taught me about a secret training technique.
First we need to plant a tree.
And then...
We'll see more next time.
The next story is "My Tree."
Episode 6
My Tree
Whose?